A Finding Aid to the Chaim Gross Papers, 1920-2004, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Photographs, circa 1921-circa 1990s; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 1.5 Linear feet Boxes 20-22
  - Photographs of People and Events, circa 1921-circa 1980s; 7.1; Archival Resource Key
    People pictured at exhibition openings and receptions in this series include Silvia Carewe, Lily Harmon, Irving Marantz, and Sol Wilson at a Jewish Museum opening (1953); Anne Brigadier, Lena Gurr, Gerrit Hondious, Joseph Kaplan, Bernard Simon, and Sabina Teichman at a 1957 opening; Bill Barrett, Helen Beling, Jose de Creeft, Philip Evergood, Vincent Glinsky, Lorrie Goulet, Roy Gusson, Cleo Hartwig, Luise Kaish, Lily Landis, and Sidney Simon at two Sculptors Guild exhibitions at Lever House; Jose de Creeft, Joseph Hirshhorn, and Raphael Soyer at 1970-1976 openings; and Gross with Alice Neel and Raphael Soyer, circa 1980s. There are also photos of the opening for Gross's 1977 retrospective at the Jewish Museum picturing Gross with artists, collectors, and gallery owners.
    Photographs are arranged by subject and chronologically thereafter.
    - Chaim Gross, circa 1940s-circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 1)
      Oversized photos housed in Box 22, Folder 5
    - Chaim Gross Family, circa 1921-circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Chaim Gross at Bedi-Makky Art Foundry, Greenpoint, Brooklyn, 1973-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Chaim Gross at Educational Alliance Art School, 1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Chaim Gross at Home with Art Collection, circa 1950s-circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 5)
      Oversized photos housed in Box 22, Folder 4
    - Chaim Gross in His Studio, circa 1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 6)
      Oversized photo housed in Box 22, Folder 5
    - Chaim Gross in His Studio, 1933-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Chaim Gross in His Studio, 1938-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Chaim Gross in His Studio, 1942-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Chaim Gross in His Studio, circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Chaim Gross in His Studio, circa 1950s-circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Chaim Gross in His Studio, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Chaim Gross in His Studio, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Chaim Gross in His Studio, 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Chaim Gross in His Studio Working on Six Days of Creation, circa 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Chaim Gross's Studio, circa 1930s-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Chaim Gross on Provincetown Beach with Others, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Chaim Gross, Photographs by Bernard Gotfryd, circa 1960s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Chaim Gross with Art Collectors and Gallery Owners, circa 1930s-circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Chaim Gross with Artists, 1926-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Chaim Gross with Artists, Isaac, Moses, and Raphael Soyer, circa 1920s-circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Chaim Gross with Others, 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Exhibition Installations, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Exhibition Installations, circa 1932-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Exhibition Installations, Associated American Artists Gallery, 1942, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 25)
      Oversized photos housed in Box 22, Folder 6
    - Exhibition Installations, Duveen-Graham Gallery (1957), Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Exhibition Installations, Whitney Museum of American Art (1959-1960), circa 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Exhibition Installations, Forum Gallery (1967), Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Exhibition Installations, Jewish Museum, Jewish Theological Seminary (1977), Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Exhibition Installations, Schulman Park, White Plains, Westchester (1985-1986), circa 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Exhibition Openings/Receptions, circa 1953-circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - Exhibition Openings/Receptions, 1970-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - Exhibition Openings/Receptions, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - Exhibition Openings/Receptions, Photos by David Lyon Hurwitz, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - Other Events, circa 1940s-circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - Other Events, circa 1960s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - Parties at Gross's Home, circa 1950s-circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - Parties at Gross's Home, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - Parties at Gross's Home, 1967, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - Oversized Chaim Gross at Home with Art Collection from Box 20, Folder 5, Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Oversized Chaim Gross from Box 20, Folder 1; Chaim Gross in His Studio from Box 20, Folder 6; Chaim Gross with Artists Isaac, Moses, and Raphael Soyer from Box 22, Folder 5, Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Oversized Exhibition Installations from Box Box 20, Folder 25, Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, circa 1930s-circa 1990s; 7.2; Archival Resource Key
    Photos of Gross's works of art primarily document sculpture executed between 1922 and the 1980s. Additional photos include sculpture installations, Gross's commissions Six Days of Creation and Ten Commandments, some of his Works Progress Administration works, stained glass windows, and watercolors and drawings.
    Photographs are arranged by subject and are roughly chronological thereafter.
    - Installations, circa 1951-circa 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - Installations, 1972-circa 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 41)
    - Off-Spring in Home of Arnold Newman, circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 42)
    - Sculpture Executed 1922-1929, circa 1930s-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 43)
    - Sculpture Executed 1930-1932, circa 1930s-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 44)
    - Sculpture Executed 1933-1934, circa 1930s-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 45)
    - Sculpture Executed 1935, circa 1930s-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 46)
    - Sculpture Executed 1937-1939, circa 1930s-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 47)
    - Sculpture Executed 1940, circa 1940s-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 48)
    - Sculpture Executed 1941-1943, circa 1940s-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 49)
    - Sculpture Executed 1944-1945, circa 1940s-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 50)
    - Sculpture Executed 1946-1947, circa 1940s-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 51)
    - Sculpture Executed 1948-1949, circa 1940s-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 52)
    - Sculpture Executed 1950-1951, circa 1950s-circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 53)
    - Sculpture Executed 1952, circa 1950s-circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 54)
    - Sculpture Executed 1953, circa 1950s-circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 55)
    - Sculpture Executed 1954, circa 1950s-circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 56)
    - Sculpture Executed 1955, circa 1950s-circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 57)
    - Sculpture Executed 1956, circa 1950s-circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 58)
    - Sculpture Executed 1957, circa 1950s-circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 59)
    - Sculpture Executed 1958, circa 1950s-circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 60)
    - Sculpture Executed 1959, circa 1950s-circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 61)
    - Sculpture Executed 1960-1961, circa 1960s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 62)
    - Sculpture Executed 1962, circa 1960s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 63)
    - Sculpture Executed 1963-1964, circa 1960s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 64)
    - Sculpture Executed 1965-1966, circa 1960s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 65)
    - Sculpture Executed 1965-1966, circa 1960s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 66)
    - Sculpture Executed 1967-1968, circa 1960s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Sculpture Executed 1969-1971, circa 1960s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Sculpture Executed 1971-1972, circa 1970s-circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Sculpture Executed 1973, circa 1970s-circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Sculpture Executed 1974-1976, circa 1970s-circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Sculpture Executed 1977-1979, circa 1970s-circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Sculpture Executed 1980-1983, circa 1980s-circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Sculpture Executed 1984-1987, circa 1980s-circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Sculpture Execution Dates Unknown, circa 1930s-circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Stained Glass Windows, Executed 1974, circa 1974-circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Six Days of Creation, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Ten Commandments, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Ten Commandments, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Watercolors and Drawings Executed 1939-1970, circa 1930s-circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - WPA Commissions, circa 1930s-circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 15)
- Unprocessed Addition, 1949-1951; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 0.2 Linear feet Box 25
  The Unprocessed Addition is comprised of three sketchbooks.
  - Unprocessed Addition, 1949-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 25)